Hello friends, my name is Chanchal and today
we will talk about the warranty policy of MRF tyres. No matter
which
category of vehicle you have, we will talk about
how much warranty is there for which type of vehicle
and what is covered in the warranty and
what is not covered and how you can make a claim. So
before knowing what is covered in the warranty, let
us know how long the
warranty is for the tyres. So MRF
provides different warranties for different tyres, like
tubular
car, tractor, OTR i.e. JCB
gets a 6 year warranty, whereas
you get a 3 year warranty in radial and non-radial track tyres and you get a
4 year warranty in commercial vehicles and small commercial vehicles.
Now this warranty is
given to you against manufacturing defects and in this claim that is passed,
you are given warranty on the basis of pro ta res
and if we talk about
what is pro ta then pro ta if we
understand it in easy terms, whenever you go to claim a tyre then
You have to pay some amount for the percentage of tyre you use,
this is called pro rata and
if we talk about what all is covered under the warranty, then
I have been in this dealership for
two and a half years, here I
see three common things, first is
air which you can see in the screen,
second is crack and third is
loose wire, these three common things are basically seen,
apart from this there is one more common thing
which is bubbling, this is seen in very few tyres,
but yes
our warranty gives you claim in bubbling also,
now let's talk about what all is
not covered in the warranty, first is
wrong use of the vehicle, if you use the vehicle for racing
or overloading, then
MRF does not provide you warranty in all these,
because what happens in racing is that if
you go beyond the kilometer rating of the tyre, then the
warranty of the tyre gets rejected
and if you do overloading also, then it gets
rejected, secondly there is
fitment issue many times  What happens is that
while getting the fitting done, the tyre gets cut
or its collar gets torn, due to this
also MRF does not provide warranty.
Thirdly, if there is less air in the vehicle,
if you drive with less air then the vehicle
runs with pressure, the tyre runs with pressure due to
which the tyre gets cracked, otherwise
in many cases they pass it, so this is
not a problem and
if we talk about how you can claim the tyre, then
you have two options for making a claim,
either you can go
to the dealership, whichever is the nearest
dealership to you, you can go to googlethalli.com
which you can see on the screen, there is a
form which has to be filled up there and
you get a receipt for it
from the dealership and the
process of making this claim, if you get it done
from the dealership then it takes something like one week
and the second option is that you can
go to the dealership and find out
where the warehouse is, then you can go
directly to the warehouse  You can go after getting the tyre
opened, it is not like that you take the vehicle
and it will open on its own there, it is not like that,
you will have to get the tyre of the vehicle opened and take it there, the
technician there
will check your tyre whether it is covered under warranty i.e. whether it has any
manufacturing defect or not,
if there is a manufacturing defect then he will charge you
pro-rata as I told you that he will
charge you some amount for the gas in the tyre and the rest he will fill up himself and
provide you a new tyre
and this warranty in MRF,
friends there is no repairing involved in it, the
tyre which you are claiming will be returned to you in absolutely new fresh
condition, so this was a small
information which I wanted to share with you,
if you have any question then you
can ask in the comment below
[Music]